{
  "id": 801,
  "themeId": 8,
  "name": "Writing and Reading metro – Quiz 1",
  "description": "Practice vocabulary related to public transportation and the metro through writing and reading exercises.",
  "version": "2.2.3",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How do you say "public transportation"?",
      "options": ["A. Transport avec les copains", "B. Transports en commun", "C. Transport commun", "D. Transports communs"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Transports en commun",
      "explanation": "About 70% of French people living in cities of more than 50 000 inhabitants use public transportation (bus, subway, tramway, train…)."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"metro line\"?",
      "options": ["A. Lignes de métro", "B. Ligne de métro", "C. Ligne de métros", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Ligne de métro",
      "explanation": "Métro is short for "métropolitain" that is itself short for « chemin de fer métropolitain » which means city railroad."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"subway map\"?",
      "options": ["A. Plan de métro", "B. Carte du métro", "C. Plane de métro", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Plan de métro",
      "explanation": "The first Parisian subway map was created in 1900 with the opening of Line 1, which linked Porte Maillot to Porte de Vincennes."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "A ticket please"? ",
      "options": ["A. Un ticket s'il vous plait ?", "B. Un ticket s'il te plait ?", "C. Un ticket merci ?", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Un ticket s'il vous plait ?",
      "explanation": "You need a ticket to get into the subway and most times to exit as well. It's best to keep it with you until you exit."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "approximately 4 million passengers"? ",
      "options": ["A. Près de 4 millions de passagers", "B. Environ 4 millions de passagers", "C. Approximativement 4 millions de passagers", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. All of the above",
      "explanation": "Approximately 4 million passengers use the Paris Metro every day."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "metro line 6 connects Charles de Gaulle-Étoile to Nation"? ",
      "options": ["A. La ligne de métro 6 relie Charles de Gaulle-Étoile à Nation.", "B. La ligne 6 relie Charles de Gaulle-Étoile à Nation.", "C. La ligne de métro 6 circule entre Charles de Gaulle-Étoile et Nation.", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. All of the above",
      "explanation": "Lines are primarily numbered 1 to 16 (with a few exceptions like 3bis and 7bis). Higher numbers generally correspond to lines built later, often serving outer suburbs."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "a metro every 2 to 5 minutes"? ",
      "options": ["A. Une métro toutes les 2 à 5 minutes", "B. Une station tous les 2 à 5 minutes", "C. Un métro toutes les 2 à 5 minutes", "D. Un métro entres 2 à 5 minutes"],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Un métro toutes les 2 à 5 minutes",
      "explanation": "In Paris, A metro is expected every 2 to 5 minutes."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"The first metro is at 5:30 AM"? ",
      "options": ["A. Le premier métro est à 5h30.", "B. Le premier métro est à cinq heures trente.", "C. Le premier métro est à cinq heures et demie du matin.", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. All of the above",
      "explanation": "It's more common to say du matin after 5h30 but people will understand nonetheless since you are talking about the first metro."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"What time is the last metro leaving\"?",
      "options": ["A. À quelle heure est le dernier métro ?", "B. À telle heure est le dernier métro ?", "C. À comment heure est le dernier métro ?", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. À quelle heure est le dernier métro ?",
      "explanation": "In Paris, the last metro of the day is scheduled to depart around 12:30 AM to 12:40 AM from Thursday to Sunday. On Fridays, Saturdays, and eves of holidays, it is between 1:30 AM and 1:40 AM approximately."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"how to get to the Louvre Museum please"? ",
      "options": ["A. Comment puis-je me rendre au Louvre s'il vous plait ?", "B. Comment se rendre au Louvre s'il vous plait ?", "C. Comment aller au Louvre s'il vous plait ?", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. All of the above",
      "explanation": "There are three stations that serve the Louvre Museum in Paris, the closest being Palais Royal-Musée du louvre"
    }
  ]
}